paymaya.com 2019-05-25

# Privacy Policy

## Our Approach to Privacy

To provide you with the best customer experience, PayMaya Philippines, Inc. (PayMaya) is committed to protecting your privacy and staying transparent with the way we handle your personal information. For this we have designed a privacy policy that will help you understand how we collect, use, store, share and protect the personal information you have entrusted us.

## Privacy Policy

Our privacy policy values and protects your personal information under the Data Privacy Act of 2012 and the laws of the Philippines. Personal information simply means any information or data that can be used to distinguish, identify or contact you.

Our Privacy Policy explains:  
• Why we collect personal information  
• What kind information we collect  
• Where we get these information  
• Who we share your information with  
• How we protect your information  
• Your choices and remedies, including how you can check and update any personal information we have about you  
• What happens if there are changes in our privacy policy

As a condition for use of our products and services, you are consenting to the Privacy Policy of PayMaya Philippines, Inc. (we, our, us) and its subsidiaries, affiliates, and subcontractors; and the collection, use, access, transfer, storage and processing of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy.

## Why we collect personal information

To improve our products and services, it is important that we collect, use, process and analyze your personal information when it is reasonable and necessary. When we can, we aggregate and anonymize this information such that you are never identified as an individual. [Aggregating simply means presenting information in segments or categories like age groups; anonymizing means removing personally identifiable information from the data].  
In particular, we are using your information to:  
1\. Manage your account, provide customer care activities, monitor the quality and security of the network, train our staff, and provide services timely and efficiently and ensure your fair and lawful use of the products and services provided by PayMaya;  
2\. Send commercial and promotional advertisements, loyalty and rewards offers, surveys, customer care and aftersales communications, and other broadcast push messages;  
3\. Share your personal data with third-party content providers or other third-party services for which you sign up;  
4\. Conduct analysis for research and marketing initiatives, including the generation of anonymized or non-personally identifiable location and mobility data to show footfall, location patterns, crowd density, and other information that may be relevant for marketing purposes;  
5\. Generate statistical insights based on usage/network information to assist the Government in planning for healthcare, disaster, and other similar initiatives;  
6\. Run credit scoring programs and initiatives, including but not limited to, providing information to the Credit Information Corporation in accordance to Republic Act No. 9510, otherwise known as the Credit Information System Act; and  
7\. Perform such other processing or disclosure that may be required under law or regulations.

In cases where your separate and full consent is given, we are also processing your personal data to:  
1\. Create your personal profile based on your interests, preferences, mobility patterns from physical locations that you may visit, and other information that may be relevant for marketing and market research purposes;  
2\. Share your personal profile based on your interests, preferences, and mobility patterns from physical locations that you may visit, to our business partners and third-party service providers;  
3\. Compute your credit score based on data collected internally within the PLDT Group and its subsidiaries and affiliates, and share your credit score to third-parties to whom you specifically instruct us to share your credit score; and  
4\. Send you information on offers, promotions, and advertisements from our business partners and third-party service providers.

## What type of information we collect

We collect information to provide better services to all of our users. This may range from the most basic like being able to offer promos that best suites the user’s to more complex use cases like which related services and digital content a user might find interesting & useful. This includes information such as:  
Who you are  
• Basic personal information like your name, date of birth, gender, nationality, address, and identity supporting documents such as SSS or passport numbers. You can check what we know about you by making a request to the PayMaya Data Privacy Officer through the contact details provided below;  
• Your credit card, bank and payment details; and  
• Your contact details like billing address, telephone number, mobile phone number, email address;  
What you use our product/services for  
• Use of virtual or physical card to purchase online  
• Use of physical card to purchase in store  
• Purchase of fast moving digital goods which includes but not limited to prepaid airtime load, prepaid cable packages, gaming e-PINs etc.  
• Utility bills payments and government contributions  
• ATM withdrawals, payments and transfers to third parties  
• Account maintenance, including change in account information and contact details  
• The device you use when to access our Products and Services (such as your mobile handset, your computer system and platform) to customize our service for you  
• No, we don’t look at the content of your text messages and we don’t listen to your calls, unless you’re talking to our hotline  
What you do with your PayMaya Account  
• This includes when and how much you reload or pay your bills; and  
• How often you access your account and why.

## Where we get these information

Your Personal Data may be obtained in many ways including through market research activities, PayMaya App, Web Portal, or Platform, through an accredited Third-Party platform or channel, and from PayMaya’s subsidiaries, affiliates, business partners, and third-party service providers.  
Information that you personally give us  
Most of the personal information we have are those that you have given us yourself. You provide us personal information when you  
• Apply for subscription/registration to our services by via the Mobile App, filling out a Service Application Form online, in one of our stores, or provide personal information to one of our TeleSales representative;  
• Get in touch with us to ask about something, file a complaint or request for service;  
• Take part in our research and surveys; and/or  
• When you apply for job with us.  
Information we collect during our relationship with you  
We also collect information as you use our products & services, like when you:  
• Use our networks - whether it is mobile, Wi-Fi, or other channels;  
• Pay your bill or purchase add-on products and services;  
• Use our apps, websites and self-service channels; and  
• Join our promos, prize raffles or reward & loyalty programs  
Information we collect from other sources  
We also collect information from commercially or publicly available sources like published directories and public documents. We may also obtain your personal information from third parties and from other sources which you have given consent for the disclosure of such information relating to you and where otherwise lawfully permitted.

## Who we share your information with

There are a variety of circumstances where we may need to disclose or share some of the information that you have provided to us. In these cases, we ensure that your personal information is disclosed on a confidential basis, and always subject to the applicable rules and regulations of the Data Privacy Act.  
We will never share, rent or sell your personal information to third parties outside PayMaya (or the group of companies of which PayMaya is part of) except in limited circumstances as noted in this policy. In some instances, we may be required to disclose your personal information to our agents, subsidiaries, affiliates, partners and other third-party agencies as part of business operations and the provision of our products and services. This means we might share your information with:  
• Our partner companies, organizations, or agencies including their sub-contractors or prospective business partners that act as our service providers, contractors, professional advisers who help us provide our products and services, for example our couriers for bill delivery and our customer contact centers for our hotline operations;  
• Other companies in the PLDT Group of companies;  
• Law enforcement and government agencies; and  
• Other companies whom you have also given consent to share your information

## How we protect your information

The integrity, confidentiality and security of your information are particularly important to us. That’s why we strictly enforce our privacy policy within the company and we have implemented technological, organizational and physical security measures that are designed to protect your information from unauthorized access, use, alteration and disclosure. We also put in effect safeguards such as:  
1\. We keep and protect your information using a secured server behind a firewall, encryption and security controls;  
2\. We restrict access to your information only to qualified and authorized personnel who hold your information with strict confidentiality;  
3\. We undergo regular audit and rigorous testing of our infrastructure’s security protocols to ensure your data is always protected; and  
4\. We let you update your information securely to keep our records accurate  
5\. We keep your information only for as long as necessary for the fulfillment of the purposes for which the information was obtained or for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims, or for legitimate business purposes, or as provided by law, rules and regulations;  
6\. We promptly notify you and the National Privacy Commission, when sensitive personal information that may, under the circumstances, be used to enable identity fraud are reasonably believed to have been acquired by an unauthorized person;

## Your choices and remedies, including how you can check and update any personal information we have about you.

You are afforded certain rights in relation to your personal data under the Data Privacy Act of 2012, which includes the right to object to processing, the right to access your data, the right to modify of inaccurate data, and the right to erasure or blocking of data.

You have a right to file a complaint with the National Privacy Commission should you feel that your personal information has been misused, maliciously disclosed, or improperly disposed, or that any of your data privacy rights have been violated. Consequently, you have a right to claim damages in case of inaccurate, incomplete, outdated, false, unlawfully obtained or unauthorized use of personal information. 

If you wish to have access to your personal information in our records; or you think that such personal information we have of you is incomplete, not up-to-date, or otherwise inaccurate; or prefer to opt-out of this privacy policy you may get in touch with our Data Privacy Officer through the contact details provided below.  
Our Contact Details:  
PayMaya Customer Service No. (632)845-7788; Domestic Toll-Free Landline: 1-800-108457788 or email: support@paymaya.com  
Data Privacy Compliance Officer: [dpo@paymaya.com](mailto:dpo@paymaya.com)

## What happens when there are changes in this policy

From time to time, PayMaya may change this privacy policy to comply with government and regulatory requirements; to adapt to new technologies and protocols; to align with industry practices; or for other legitimate purposes. You will always be provided notice if these changes are material and, if we are required by law, we will also obtain your consent.

## Website Privacy Policy

The policies below are applicable to the Web site and affiliate sites of PayMaya Philippines Inc. found at www.paymaya.com. Please be advised that the practices described in this Privacy Policy apply only to information gathered online at our Web site. They do not apply to information that you may submit to us offline or to Web sites maintained by other companies or organizations to which we may link or may have link through us.  
By visiting our Web site, you are accepting the practices described in our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Web site.  
PayMaya collects personal information, voluntarily submitted by visitors to the Web site, which enables us to respond to requests for publications, distribute e-newsletters, process employment inquiries and respond to requests for more information or assistance. PayMaya adheres to the highest standards of ethical practices in all of our operations and is dedicated to protecting the privacy of all visitors to our Web site. Except as disclosed below, we do not sell, barter, give away, rent or permit anyone outside of PayMaya to use your personal information.  
We occasionally use third-party agents, subsidiaries, affiliates and partners to perform functions such as creative design, marketing, analytics, programming, site maintenance, providing customer service, etc., on our behalf. These entities have access to the personal information needed to perform their functions and are contractually obligated to maintain the confidentiality and security of any personal information collected from the Web site. They are restricted from using, selling, distributing or altering these data in any way other than to provide the requested services to the Web site.  
We may also use or disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to  
(a) conform to applicable law or comply with legal process served on us or the Website;  
(b) protect and defend our rights or property, the Web site or our users, and  
(c) act under emergency circumstances to protect our safety and security and those of our affiliates, agents and the users of the Web site or the public in general.  
PayMaya also collects anonymous information to help us tailor the Web site to visitor interests and concerns. We use "cookies" to help us understand which parts of our Web site are the most popular, where our visitors are going and how much time they spend there. The information that is gathered through cookies is used solely to assist in improving Web site design and function. This Web site is functional without the retention of cookies. You may elect to block cookies from this site through your browser settings. PayMaya strives to protect the transmission of any information submitted by visitors. PayMaya does not warrant that transmission of data will be completely secured, and any and all submissions are at the visitor's risk.  
This Web site may contain links to sites operated by third parties. Please be advised that the practices described in this Privacy Policy do not apply to information gathered through these other Web sites.  
Please remember that any information that you may share in public areas, such as message boards or feedback sections, becomes public, and therefore this Privacy Policy does not apply to any information you choose to make public. Please be careful about what you disclose, and do not post any personal information that you expect to keep private.  
The Web site is published in the Republic of the Philippines and is subject to laws of the Republic of the Philippines. If you are located in a country outside the Republic of the Philippines and voluntarily submit personal information to us, you thereby consent to the general use of such information as provided in this Privacy Policy and to the transfer of that information to, and/or storage of that information in, the Republic of the Philippines. PayMaya shall not be liable under any circumstances for damages resulting from use of information collected from visitors to the site.   
PayMaya may change this Privacy Policy to reflect, among others, changes in the way we collect visitor information.  
Questions and comments should be directed to this email address: dpo@paymaya.com  
Last updated: 21 May 2018

Go [here](https://paymaya.com/partners/?__hstc=162943075.046da1ff91ae9efdf97fee913382f61d.1580497840758.1580497840758.1580497840758.1&__hssc=162943075.1.1580497840758&__hsfp=3924935683) to see PayMaya's list of partners.
